Welcome to the 10th episode of Under the
Hood. Um, 10th episode is almost like an
anniversary.
>> It is.
>> Um, so, uh, today we are going to talk
about something quite exciting. We're
talking about security, hacking, that
kind of thing. And, uh, with me today
have Jonathan. Welcome, Jonathan. Thank
you, Vincent.
>> Um, so tell us a bit about yourself and
tell us about what you do in relation to
security.
>> Okay. Well, my name is of course
Jonathan Davis. I'm a uh security
program manager on the the BIC security
team. So BIC is the um business and
industry co-pilots. It's the business
unit that includes business central, but
it also includes all of the Dynamics
products and the power platform.
>> So your role is broader than just
business central.
>> It's broad broader than just business
central. Although my origins are in
business central. So I started off there
and because Business Central is such a
got such a good security culture, you
know, um I sort of evolved from there
into these kind of bigger roles. So
yeah, we're responsible for um the
security of all of the power platform
and and Dynamics 365, which is, you
know, quite a responsibility.
>> Yeah. Right. Okay. So before we get into
more specific into um Business Central,
let's talk a little bit about, you know,
security in general. Um, you hear a lot
of in the news, you know, people hear a
lot about security hackers. So, is that
how how bad is it? Uh, are hackers
really at the gate? You know, are we
should we be concerned?
>> Yeah, I think we should be concerned.
Uh, I think the hackers kind of are at
the gates a little bit. Um, although I
think that things are getting better. Um
I think that awareness uh out there
about the importance of cyber security
uh the reporting on it uh the just the
general response from the industry has
been better. I mean certainly here as
you probably know here within Microsoft
there's a
>> we've uh security has just been
massively rep prioritized in the last
year or so
>> due to some
>> some fairly severe incidents that we
were subjected to. So I think that the
it's a kind of a mixture. You know,
there's a lot of people that are
incentivized to sort of say that, well,
you know, that, you know, the the sky is
falling in and everything is falling
apart and it's getting worse and worse,
>> but the threat is still present.
>> The threat is very present and I think
it's quite I don't think that people
quite appreciate how ruinous it can be
>> uh for both individuals and
organizations if they do experience a
severe incident. Um, I mean, we've got a
a very special responsibility because we
hold the keys of the kingdoms for so
many
>> businesses. So many organizations are
dependent on us, Microsoft and also in
Business Central. Um, but I think that
what we're seeing so more broadly is is
a growing awareness amongst normies,
amongst ordinary people. You're probably
getting calls from your elderly parents
and all the rest of it.
>> Um, unfortunately there's a lot of
alarmism out there. You know, just
recently there was this thing about 16
billion passwords have been exposed.
>> Uh, and there had elderly parents
calling up, you know, have I been
hacked? Uh that's an example where there
is an industry of people that are
designed to sort of inflate and
exaggerate the cyber security story in
unhelpful ways. Those 16 billion
passwords were in fact collections of
all the previous dumps and a couple a
smattering of other ones.
>> So it was not like a new
>> it wasn't new stuff. It was just you
know people just keep making lists or
recombining them but it was reported by
sort of certain news you know got wide
widespread was in the BBC and all the
rest of it.
>> But just to be clear that's there still
a real thing there. There are such a
thing as lists of password and databases
of password circulating around.
>> Exactly.
>> And uh if you go if you use products
like Last Pass or other thing, they will
tell you this password is been
compromised and that's that's that's a
thing. It's not just a
>> I think there's a good side and a bad
side. So I think the bad side is just
like you know uh it people are
terrified. But the good side is that it
makes people use password managers. It
makes people use pass keys. Makes people
use multiffactor authentication. And
they also realize uh you know when
people do ask you well why why should I
care if that password ends up in a
breach.
>> The main reason uh that sort of why we
we talk about not having password reuse
for example is that you put in the same
password that you use for your bank in
with the the cinema.
>> The cinema gets hacked and now they've
got the password for your bank. And this
is exactly how so many hacks happen.
>> It's it's credential reuse or password
spraying. I mean, right now we in
Microsoft are experienced sometimes
billions, if not trillions of attempts
of people that are taking these rainbow
tables and other lists of of passwords,
username and password pairs that they've
stolen from people. You know, for
example, there's a type of malware
called an info stealer that when it
executes on a computer, it grabs all the
cookies and all the passwords out of the
mostly the browsers. It's not so good at
getting and it puts them it gives them
to attackers. then attackers can just
reuse these or sell them on and they can
try them you know against sort of more
you know more difficult targets like
like businesses. So I think you know
just to summarize I think that it's it
is important that people um realize that
they're that these cyber security
practices people keep going on about
they're kind of minimum bar now to stay
safe in this digital world
>> and there's also this I don't have the
statistics but I know that um that
there's a lot of of companies and
businesses who got attacked and typical
typical thing is ransomware attacks or
or you know denial of service attacks
and they you know they're not too proud
of the fact that their security is maybe
not quite up to date. So, so a lot of
these incident they they get unnoticed
and unreported. they just pay the
attackers or and and they don't tell
about it because imagine you have your
own business and you get attacked. You
know, how much do you want to ad
advertise about it? You probably want
to, you know, keep quiet about it. You
know, you don't want your customers to
know about it. You know, these kind of
things. So, a lot of these things also
get a little bit unnoticed. Um
>> I think that many of people that have
worked in incident response, they'll
tell you that the the first thing that
happens is okay fine, we've evicted the
the the the you know, the the the
attackers and then it's like cover it
up,
>> you know, don't tell anybody. Uh I think
that there is a big drive now. Some of
it's led by legislation and some of it's
led by just industry best practices for
people to to fess up because it
shouldn't be about victim blaming.
>> Mhm.
>> I mean a determined attacker will be
able to get I mean we we talk there is
there's this phrase which is which they
use for you know ATPs you know advanced
APS advanced persistent threats.
>> Um what we sometimes use we prefer is
sort of high focus high skill high
resource. In other words, if someone
kind of wants to hack you, if they've
got enough resources and enough skill,
they'll probably find a way.
>> The game is to just make it harder and
harder and harder for people. Make
yourself a hard target.
>> It's to slow people down and and and and
you know, force them out. And I think
with the ransomware epidemic, it started
hitting individuals. Firstly, it was
just ordinary people that were getting a
kind of a virus, but the virus had
encrypted their stuff. And then the
attackers suddenly realized that this
was small money compared to what they
could get out of institutions. So they
started going after you know companies
and they often now target the real some
of the softest and most vulnerable. They
go for schools, they go for
municipalities, they go for hospitals.
>> These are people with no honor.
>> Is it fair to say that you know Business
Central is a small and medium business
product? So a lot of our customers and
partners are you know in in the small
and and medium business industry. there
are they are maybe more obvious targets
because they are at least in that
segment where you know big companies
like Microsoft you know uh you know
other you know large corporation they of
course they have you know they do all
the right things about securities and a
lot of yes they have a lot of money but
they're a lot harder to hack whereas
they probably you know one could imagine
there's a lot of small businesses who
have invested in security maybe not as
much as they should you know I I just an
anecdotal story I was talking to
somebody you know I won't reve any name,
but they were saying, you know, they
they had an on-rem business and we can
get back to that, you know, onrem
versus, you know, the cloud with
Business Central, but they were saying,
>> uh, you know, I have a, you know, why
why should I be concerned about
security? I have a firewall,
>> you know.
>> Yeah. So,
what's your reaction to that, you know,
because I think a lot of I mean, it's
not it's a genuine comment and and and I
think it's a it's, you know, um, I
understand why people would think, you
know, okay, I have my I have my server
in my basement. I have a firewall. I'm
safe. Yeah. You know, so what what
what's your comment on that?
>> Look, I feel I I feel genu genuinely
sorry for people for ordinary people out
there because the entire software
industry has papered over the cracks for
30 years.
>> I mean, software is cheap because we're
we're not we're we're indemnified
against the consequences of our
mistakes.
>> This is the original sin of the software
industry, which is that if your if you
crash a car because your brakes fail,
then you know your car company's going
to have to recall all of those products
and they're going to have to pay
compensation to the people injured.
That's not the case for the software
industry. As a consequence, software is
a lot cheaper than it would be if the if
it were otherwise. But there has not
really been a strong incentive to
prioritize security.
>> So we have walked all of ourselves into
this situation and ordinary people
shouldn't have to be experts on
security. They have an expectation that
the software and the things which we
provide them are secure
>> and they're often misinformed by again
the sort of the snake oily type people
that say, "Oh, all you need is a
firewall." And I do think that that is
pretty regrettable really because I I I
feel sorry for people. Uh I really do
think that it's not fair. I mean, and
you talked about the small to mediumsiz
businesses. You're entirely right about
that. They are often the absolutely most
vulnerable people. uh you know Whale
who's the security champ for uh Business
Central along with Ed uh we did a talk
at directions a couple of years ago a
long one you know a kind of multi
session two 45 minutes talking about uh
partner security and to some degree
personal security because there's an
overlap or security for SMBs
>> because we we we we realized that those
businesses are probably the most
vulnerable. They're in the perfect sweet
spot for ransomware attackers. Some of
them are kind of getting big. You got
two 200 employees, let's say. You might
be dealing with tens or even hundreds of
millions of dollars worth of of revenue,
but you don't you've got like a person
over there who's half of their job is to
be a cyber security person. You don't
have a dedicated sock. You don't have a
dedicated cyber security team.
>> People ransomware people know about
this. They're scanning. They're looking.
They've got uh you know, people don't
realize that these are big businesses.
You're not up against the guy in his
basement.
>> Ransomware crews like Revel or whatever,
they these are large organizations.
>> They're organized groups. They are not
>> they go to offices. is this this
romantic picture or whatever it is that
people have that's you know largely
conveyed by Hollywood movies uh of this
guy with a you know with a with a you
know
>> breach the firewall
>> yeah exactly I mean you know in in a
basement that's that's kind
>> matrix text and then suddenly that fills
in the password one by one yeah it
doesn't yeah so that's it's not like
that
>> exactly and I do think that so there is
a a there is a push now uh you know one
of the things which we're very forceful
on with with SFI, the secure future
initiative is is secure by default. You
know, we've often, you know, since the
70s, we've had all these security
principles like lease privilege and
secure by default, but they haven't
really had traction.
>> Mhm.
>> And that loops back to what you were
saying. It should it I remember, you
know, may not remember this, but the uh
with Windows XP when it originally
shipped, it didn't have a firewall. So
any ports, any services that were
running on this, they were exposed to
the internet. And the first versions of
the kind of built-in firewall with
service pack 2 um they were maybe I'm
wrong but I I remember that the first
thing was it was kind of block bad. So
it was open everywhere and then oh
someone is trying to you know attack me
from this IP address and I'll block it.
>> And then the fundamental mental model
switch was no no block everything and
allow list.
>> Mhm.
>> That was transformational. That suddenly
boosted sort of network security anyway
for those Windows computers massively.
This was after these various worms and
other things had had forced our hand.
>> Um, and I think that the the what is
incumbent on the software industry and
it's very close to the heart for in Bick
and in business central I know this is
that it's secure by default when you
switch it on it's secure and you have to
read the documents and to really strive
to screw it up by messing with the
configurations to make it insecure.
That's the objective now
>> because I do think that the the days of
basically saying well you know you have
to read a book and you have to get a
university level education on cyber
security in order to operate your
business with our software it's not
acceptable anymore. Yeah. And I mean is
that fair to say that um security is so
complex, so difficult these days that
you know you should let it you as your
point is like you should let
professional take care of like you know
the Microsoft cloud for example Azure is
secure by default. We're doing a lot. We
have, you know, really professional
people, experts in that area who do a
lot of work and and you know, really,
you know, know what they are doing and
they take a lot of the out a lot of the
of the, you know, the heat and the
concern you should have around your your
your service rather than, you know, if
you try to host it yourself. Uh, that's
just, you know, um,
>> you're absolutely right. I think you're
going to get hacked if you
>> look there there are I mean there are
circumstances where you want to have air
gapping and hostings yourselves and
certain governments and so on but I
think there's no doubt uh and people are
going to think that there were kind of
marketing shills but the fact is that
you get a kind of the network effect
benefits
um and it works a little bit like this
if you imagine that you are part of uh
you're you're a business central
customer and um we experience some kind
of an attempted attack against you uh
maybe it is say a credential stuffing,
you know, people trying multiple
attempts to login using username and
password pair or whatever else and or
somebody else as part of this huge
network of people that we work with and
we work with, you know, Google and
Amazon and and Apple and, you know, all
manner of industry sharing intelligence,
sharing threat intelligence. So, let's
say we get some notification that a
specific IP address or, you know, is is
malicious,
>> we can cascade that to all of our
customers immediately. So a single
customer is attacked or even compromised
and then we can plug that into our
systems to defend everybody else.
>> So what we have is a kind of a
collective strength or that that comes
inherently with that.
>> The other thing is you're entirely right
with highly complex systems.
It's very easy to make a mistake. You
get one and all you need to do is make
get one thing wrong basically uh and all
of a sudden you you're exposed. I mean
countless people have I mean I don't
know if you remember back in the day
when some people used to leave their you
know they would expose their C drives to
the internet and you know there was some
good Samaritans who would go and put a
text file on there saying you know
please can you like block you know not
share your your C drive
>> um I think today what's happening is
that many people realize that um
especially for these technologies which
a lot of people are using so let's say
you know containerization or advanced
networking and all the rest of it you
can you can roll your
You can do that if you have a home lab.
Uh you can if you've got a very
compelling business case, but there's no
doubt that if you leave it to
professionals who are, as you say,
secure by default, watched by network
operations centers staffed by the best
in the world using threat intelligence
that is the absolute freshest.
>> Um you get an you get an immediate
security yield from that. So I think
that it it there's no doubt in my mind
that customers would be well advised to
sort of take take shelter in the cloud.
>> Um it's a good picture. I like
>> yeah you know sort of it's a port in a
storm and I and I do think that you know
some people would counter and say well
you know cloud is very complex and
people mess things up and it's got its
own complexities. There's no doubt about
that for people that are buil
potentially building their own solutions
or making you know building on our past
but for the SAS products that's not the
case
>> but even in shum as a resol from a
resource standpoint I mean Microsoft has
you know large amount of resources in
terms of people you know and not only
machines and you know there are
constantly you know uh monitoring and
and all these the tooling and all that
we have but also a lot of people working
on security whereas you know if you have
a small business you know how many you
know you can't I mean Can do can you
afford to hire a security expert? Yeah.
And you need to be of a certain size
from from a business standpoint before
it makes sense to have a security expert
in your team.
>> You're entirely right. I don't think
people realize how much goes into proper
security proper 21st century security.
Uh it is there is an enormous amount of
work that goes into I mean we because of
the nature of this business because of
the importance of trust and security
because how critical it is to us and our
own reputation to make sure that we also
have this duty of care to all of our
customers.
>> So we are undoubtedly elite but we have
had large customers come into us for
EBCS and all the rest of us and we've
asked them about their security
practices and found out absolute horror
stories. You know, for example, all code
that chips from from from us from
Business Central is reviewed uh or all
systems have, you know, a threat
modeling exercise. So that is reviewed
by a security expert. A threat model is
created. That threat model is assessed.
The risks are tabulated. The mitigations
for those risks are listed out as as
action items. They're tracked in a
system.
>> Um and then and only then is the thing
cleared for release or all that. and and
we've we've maintained that even in the
age of AI where there's enormous
pressure to push out AI features and
respond to the AI moment the SLT made a
made a judgment at the early days of uh
you know in 2022
>> hey all of these AI features need to go
through the professional security teams
like my own it was very hard work for us
we were doing six seven reviews a day
but that is the kind of thing which we
just don't see this is a this again this
is the security development life cycle
it's been around for 20 years it was
stems from 200 2003 from the trustworthy
computing era,
>> but it's just not practiced out there.
Other basic things like code scanning,
>> static analysis,
>> vast amounts of customers and small
businesses, they just don't do this.
They just have
>> no code from, you know, business central
code go through the scanning and
>> through the cops and the various other
things. Yeah.
>> A lot of static analysis, finding out,
you know, is there any any code that's
potentially could um
>> we had a customer issues.
>> Yeah, exactly. I mean, not to not to
mention names. Uh we had a a large
customer that came in a Danish customer
that was we were asking about their uh
you know here we have this this concept
of the secure admin workstation or saw
as we call it uh and uh these are
specialist devices that we use to access
production systems are completely
separate from our our corporate systems.
And they're very controlled like we can
install anything on these other than the
things that are mandated or occur. So
that in order to avoid that you get a
machine into a production environment
that that potentially can contain
>> malware or they're extremely locked
down. They go through a specialist VPN.
You have to you need a second factor
physical sort of dongle UB key to be
able to even log in and use these
things.
>> And we were asking this customer, do you
have something like this? And they were
like, oh no, we've got 4,000 engineers.
all of them can access the production
databases. So I said, you know, you're
one you're one engineer, one click
>> from potentially having a compromised
endpoint that's going to be able to read
your production database. So these
concepts of of segmentation of of lease
privilege of zero trust uh the things
which are bread and butter
>> uh you know building up the SDL and all
the way through you know through to
operational security the the the
monitoring the constant vigilance and
assessment the AI powered uh kind of
signal boosting that we have these are
things that they are they have evolved
because we've been attacked a lot uh
they're the benefits of scale because
we've got this huge estate with Entra we
can see these these this these attack
profiles everywhere. So these businesses
and people that are kind of rolling
their own, they reasonably can't be
expected to to achieve the same levels
of vigilance and capability as people
like ourselves and we don't and in a way
that's what we're saying is hey don't
bother
>> you know we'll take care of that. The
promise to you is that we'll take care
of that for you. Uh of course there's
always a uh you know we have the the
joint responsibility model. There are
things which the customer will always be
responsible for and our job is to for
those pieces of it to make sure that
they can do their jobs. So for example,
we ship an awful lot of auditing and
security logs to purview so that
customers can can see can also make
their own alerts because maybe they they
can spot anomalies better than we can or
they can see things which are which we
can't because of privacy for example
like exactly who it was that did a
certain action. So it's not just that we
take care of the the the sort of the
platform, the substrate and the the SAS
layer. Uh we also have a duty to make
sure that we educate our customers which
we do. I mean in business central there
are almost always security talks at all
of the main conferences.
>> Yeah, we also have this bounty program
like which um they talk a little bit
about it. So
>> yeah, the bounty program, the Dynamics
365 bounty program,
>> you know, that is one of the big
successes that we've had in the last few
years. I remember uh I remember having
large debates with uh several of the the
executives at the time about the the
wisdom of it. Um
>> but what is it? I mean
>> Okay. Sorry. So the bounty program is
that we essentially pay people to to
report security bugs to us
vulnerabilities.
>> So if you find if you find a bug, you'll
get a Yeah. You get a fat loan.
>> Exactly. You'll get a you'll get a
credit.
>> You'll be if the CV is assigned, you'll
get your name next to it and of course
you'll get money. And we have people
that
>> if you go and want to you know get earn
some money you look for look for a
vulnerability and we'll you know we'll
we contact us
>> and we think it's fair uh you know it's
responsible disclosure. So instead of
the bad guys and girls getting these
bugs as part of an exploit chain as part
of a you know there is an industry that
creates zero days and exploits and sells
them to attackers. You know there is a
sort of a shadow world a bit like
Stranger Things an underworld that's
that's there. So
>> so what's a zero day? Do you hear that
all the time? I just watched that
Netflix series, very good one with
Robert Nero, by the way, zero days. So,
what what is a zero day? You hear that
that expression all the time?
>> I mean, a zero day just means uh a
vulnerability that is that the bad that
the that the sort of attackers know
about before the the vendors do or we
know about it. There are
>> so as opposed to there's a certain
number of vulnerabilities that are known
that can patched potentially.
>> They've been patched. Yeah. So they're
out there and then there's you know
>> they're out there but maybe they are
they are problem if people haven't
installed the patches or get on to the
latest version but they are known
vulnerability but then there's the one
>> the ones we don't know about
>> we don't know about and this is a zero
day because we don't and they are
potentially more dangerous because we
don't have a patch for it.
>> Yeah.
>> So they can be exploed.
>> Yeah. Zero days are a little bit
fetishized. You know they Netflix things
like that various others they will make
the point that oh there's a zero day and
some people say
>> sounds cool.
>> Sounds cool. Yeah, there's no doubt that
zero days are very dangerous. They are
used uh by sophisticated attackers in
very very effective ways. Uh take for
example um
the some of the statebacked actors that
like to steal cryptocurrency. They have
very sophisticated teams that would
chain together multiple zero days. They
had a zero day in in Chrome uh sandbox
escape and then they chained that up
with something else and they they used
it to to strong effect. But most
hacking, most successful breaches have
nothing to do with zero days. They
really and even most bugs most bugs
don't turn into vulnerabilities that are
used only I think 5% of security bugs
end up being weaponized or we actually
see being used out there.
>> Yeah. So I'm talking about which I I I
think again I don't have the the
statistics but a lot of the hacking
actually social engineering right
>> a lot of it social engineering a lot of
>> it's a lot easier to you know call
somebody and pretend you're somebody
else or and get their password or get
you know get them to do something or
even you were talking about before you
know an organization with 4,000
engineers employees and yeah one of them
you know one of them got get disgruntled
or fired or whatever or get angry with
the and they go and sell and not even
maybe not even the person itself would
do something but they would go and sell
some you know something to
>> they do I mean look there was a a
cryptocurrency uh actually Coinbase
>> was compromised recently they had some
contractors in a in a in a third country
uh they had very strict controls on the
computers these folks just taking
pictures of the screens with their cell
phones they had been compromised by
criminals that were paying them they're
watching hundreds of millions of dollars
worth of transactions every day and
they're paid peanuts so of course that's
an massive boost to the insider threat
problem.
>> Um, and we so you know, yes, I think
that the uh, you know, just back to the
whole kind of zero day thing, it's very
work a day stuff that gets people
compromised. Most of it's identity
compromise now. Uh, you know, reuse
credits, lack of multiffactor
authentication, sometimes password
spraying, a lot of social engineering.
You know, I call up the help desk and I
can convince somebody to, oh, my MFA,
I'm I'm Vincent. I'm a really important
guy and I've got a meeting now in a
minute and my I can't get into my Can
you reset it for me? And, oh, no, no,
no. I'm you know who I am. And of course
these poor people panic and they do it.
Uh so that's a you know a very common
social engineering thing is uh SIM
swapping. It's less it's a bit more
robust in Europe but in America it's
trivally easy. You know all you need to
do is buy off a manager in in one of
these phone company boutiques like in a
shop and they can then reset the SIM
card. So that you know people that are
using that to get SMS as a multiffactor
authenticator. That's a disaster. That's
why we advise people do not use SMS as a
as a multiffactor thing because uh it's
it's compromised. Also the the the telos
are often highly vulnerable and those
protocols are not safe. But you know
just to on the on the b on the bounty
program because I do think that this is
very a very interesting area.
We we of course want to incentivize
people to come and disclose to us
responsibly and we pay a lot. Uh on my
team we have a we have a red teamer
>> um who is gifted
>> and he was the the most successful
uh bounty uh Dynamics 365 and Power Plat
Bounty person
>> and we we actually went after him and
begged him to join us.
>> Okay.
>> Even though he would take a financial
hit joining us because these some of
these people can make literally
millions.
>> So he would make more money with
bounties.
>> He would make more money than he would
working for Microsoft.
True.
>> But of course he picked his
>> He must be pretty good then. He is
brilliant.
>> Uh but you know, I also think that these
people that can earn that kind of money,
that are that skill, they're not that
they're often not that motivated by
that. He's motivated by interest and
coming inside and seeing where the where
the where the bodies are buried and
being able to read the code bases and
actually do some good. I mean, the thing
is that he can come in and sweep up
whole classes of bugs.
>> Uh and has had a you know, massive
impact on doing this. We have had
partners and other people report you
know some pretty big bugs that have had
they got into the hands of of of
attackers would have caused us a lot of
problems. But
>> can you tell a story? I mean like
anonymize of course but something where
you know like maybe a close call or when
we had
>> look I think so yeah the I think that
most people would be quite shocked and
terrified to realize how many close
calls every business has.
>> Mhm.
>> It's only whether you know it or not. Um
people often say when we announce it we
become more and more transparent over
the years we you know a few months ago
we started reporting all of our cloud
bugs
>> the things which we were not obligated
to to reveal because they didn't have
you know CVs they weren't assigned a
kind of a CV score um because that's a
good sign when you are actually when
people are finding them and sweeping
them up it means that they're not out
there in the population so I mean I
don't have any there are quite a lot of
examples
But I think one of the a classic example
which is not related to us are spectre
and meltdown you know from uh several
years ago. Their researchers discovered
uh speculative execution bug in in these
Intel chipsets and and and they
essentially responsibly disclosed it.
The companies formed a co coalition of
30 or so organizations. I mean it was
unbelievable. for nine months. People in
Microsoft work with people in in Apple
and Google and Adobe and and every you
name it, 30 companies, uh the Linux
Foundation and various others to stage
it so that we could get everything
patched before this thing was revealed.
It was Rumble two weeks before the sort
of announce date because some clever
people said, "Hang on a minute. Why are
they doing this patch in the Linux
kernel and they're also doing this,
this, and this?" And they put it put it
together. But that was a great example
where something would have been truly
ruinous had that got out.
>> And I think that uh you know across the
board these security researchers are
doing fantastic work. They are like
really they're like an extended security
team. I mean we often say in in in that
we we describe we end our presentation
by saying we're one blue team.
>> Mhm.
>> I mean we in Microsoft we in business
central and our partners and our
customers we are one blue team. We are
all linked together. Can you explain
maybe where this red team maybe some
people the red team blue team thing
comes from military war games and
exercises like in the so in in the
military and unfortunately cyber
security is full of military metaphors.
It's kind of it's just the the boyish
>> origins of it. It's kind of changing and
we're moving out of that. But the red
team was played the attacker the enemy
and the blue team played the the the
sort of the goodies simulation
basically.
>> It's a simulation. It was a war game.
>> Yeah. We had one we did one for for BC.
precisely a while ago where we invited
some so we invited some people from the
red team
>> and they uh and they tried to bridge
into BC and we had a blue team where
people excuse me try to defend it.
>> Yeah, we have those. So that that's
interesting because that was actually
the origin story of the uh and look many
years have passed so I think it's safe
to tell the story. In 2019 we we got the
what was then the Azure uh red team
>> uh Craig Nelson and his team. Now it's
now it's just the Microsoft red team. Uh
these are some of the most skilled
hackers in the world.
>> Mhm.
>> They came over here to to Copenhagen.
They spent a week,
>> more than a week with us with a series
of engineers from Business Central,
including the people that are now the
security managers for Business Central.
They took all these engineers in and
they did what's called a ride along. So
here the red team takes engineers and
they they they hack or attempt to hack
Business Central in this case exactly
the same way a highly skilled, highly
focused adversary would or an AP. It
could be a ransomware gang, it could be
a state actor.
>> And they went to work and it was amazing
to see the techniques that they used,
the the surveillance, the various stages
of it. And there were some successes.
The the team learned a lot. Uh it it led
to a fairly extensive amount of cleanup
work, but it's great. It was an
examination of where things were and it
was very surprising. The things that we
thought would be problematic weren't and
the things that we thought were taken
care of,
>> you know, like uh you know the they used
all manner of attacks because that's
what attackers do. They look at your can
they pivot from your development
environments into your production
environments. Can we compromise members
of your leadership team? And then once
we compromise members of the leadership
team, can we use those stolen
credentials to fool other people into
clicking malicious links? I mean, they
they showed us all of the techniques
that attackers would use.
>> And then but very shortly after that, uh
I I was working with the people from
from the from the um from MSRC, the bug
bounty.
>> Mhm. And I remember saying, "Hey,
listen. We we we want to set up this
Dynamics 365 bug bounty and you know,
and we also want to make sure that that
that and I remember that uh our our then
one of our then directors was saying,
"Are we sure we can do this?" Like, do
we want to We've just had the red team
operation. We're still cleaning up from
that. Do we want to have the attention
of these people on us? Isn't that going
to put us at risk? And uh I I explained
that actually if if there is hidden
risk, it's there.
>> Yes.
>> And the attackers will find it. find it.
Yeah,
>> it's far better to have these like
security researchers or finders as we
call them looking at us and examining us
and incentivized to look at us to find
the bugs and report them to us and clean
them up
>> before they can be used against us. And
thankfully, Touchwood so far that's
worked out very well. We've had, you
know, all manner of of uh of of bugs
reported to us over the years. uh and
they have gone a very long way to making
sure that business central and the wider
dynamics 365 and power platform are are
very secure.
>> So what what um what would you recommend
to our partners and and developers out
there for you know BC developers you
know you know partner channel to do to
make sure that their solution remains
secure. I mean we're doing a lot of
clear though we're doing a lot of work
to keep the service secure you know the
SAS secure Azure and you know all the
all the code we ship from business
central is you know go through all the
the things we talked about before so
there's a lot of scooting around it but
what what can they do because they they
can they also have a responsibility
towards their own customers
>> um so what will you what would you
advise them to to do
>> I think the simplest thing would be for
them to to follow the security
development life cycle that is a very
mature, very complete and absolutely
brilliant
>> well doumented
>> well doumented security framework.
>> We're going to put some links in the
description.
>> Yeah, please do. And I think that the
you know there are a lot of great
resources out there. You know there are
uh one of the things which I love um is
these we have these CISO workshops
>> which are out there. There's a video
section with accompanying decks that are
made available to people. They're aimed
at chief information security officers
but they're actually open. Anybody with
half a brain could understand them. And
it lays out the entire kind of world of
security. How these different pieces
hang together. You know, what is
security assurance? What is operational
security? What is security architecture?
What is posture management? These terms
like what is this stuff? They're they're
ways of just describing different jobs
that need to be done. So there's some
terminology around it, but also some
concepts that are
>> they're useful concepts to understand
because someone's got to be got to make
sure that our that our products don't
have bugs that the code that we're
shipping if if we're taking dependencies
on components for example, we want to
make sure that we have got we're updated
to the latest ones. We use tools
internally like component governance or
there are many external tools that do
the same thing. They look at the various
dependencies and they say hey there's a
vulnerability in that. Make sure you
patch that before you ship it. So that's
just one small part of it. I mean one
thing which I would definitely say is a
hugely powerful and advantageous thing
for for partners to do uh a couple of
things actually well several one is
threat modeling people don't they don't
really this is this is rarely done
outside of elite companies and it's a
pity because this is probably one of the
most powerful mental models that you can
apply
>> it's quite easy to deploy it doesn't
take a lot of
>> threat modeling is deceptively simple I
mean we made a 5minute video for
engineering resources here within
Microsoft it really just involves this
you sit down as a team
>> I mean this is the super I mean you're
going to mail because people be like
that's not direct modeling but
essentially you sit down as a team you
understand the system like what is the
system that's why you diagram it out
what are the different parts who are the
dramatist persona like what's connecting
up so there's a database that's a
compute engine that's AKS there's a user
that's a browser blah blah blah you
diagram it and you connect things up
then you analyze that system with an
attacker's mindset and say what could go
wrong here
>> they look at boundaries and things like
that
>> you have you have trust boundaries and
all the rest of it there's again so
threat modeling and guidance on threat
modeling is available on on on the mic
as Microsoft resources there's abundant
training you don't need an awful lot of
training again this is deceptively
simple understand the system ask what
could go wrong then when you figure out
oh actually they could break in here or
that's a weak identity or we are
exposing that to the internet we don't
have a firewall here then you list out
all of the these are risks these are
threats and then for each threat you say
you ask yourself okay what are we going
to do about it what's the mitigation or
the fix or do we accept it and this is
another thing which I think people uh
you actually made a great point a few
years ago. We're not advanced and sort
of good security people are not security
absolutists.
Remember that they're part of a business
that has to ship value to customers.
>> So you can't just be saying no no no no
no all the time. The job of a of a
highly competent security person is
actually decide when things don't have
to be fixed. You're you're the true
security professionals are trying to
find that balance between shipping value
and maintaining operational speed versus
security. But I think for our partners
just to come back to your question about
what can our partners do uh security
development life cycle that's for the
shipping of of their actual resources.
Uh I think we'll make that our deck
available that we presented at at
directions which is the
>> which is a really a a a primer on how
small businesses can really armor
themselves take themselves from the
lowest percentile to the top percentiles
of things by just considering keeping an
inventory of what they have making sure
that it's up to date and so on. Identity
management is a huge part of this. Uh so
much so much compromise happens because
of compromised identities. You know,
using weak passwords, not using
multiffactor authentication. Uh you
know, I'm I strongly encourage partners
to really just look into this, mandate
this in their their entra tenants, their
their M365 tenants, uh multiffactor
authentication and good multiffactor
authentication.
>> You know, the the preferably not SMS. Is
that what you're saying?
>> Definitely not SMS. Uh you know, we we
actually use so-called fishing resistant
MFA. M
>> so these would be things like pass keys.
Uh this would mean that that if this
enforces you know proof of presence. So
>> you know because attackers are getting
good at gaming people or putting up a
fake page that says type in your
multiffactor authentication and then
they just proxy it across but this one
it brings up a little barcode. I mean
many people in Denmark are familiar with
with MIT ID that has a similar concept
or it has to be in Bluetooth range you
know.
>> So that prevents the kind of man-to-he
type of attack right.
>> Yeah. It it essentially just prevents
people from being able to spoof and you
know and I do think that uh
>> there are you know these small things
can go a huge way by have by integrating
threat modeling into your development
life cycle just asking question what
could go wrong how could we improve this
if we had to break into the system what
would we do if we lost the keys or the
certificates or whatever and you ask
that question and you list out those
threats and you mitigate them you make
sure that you're patching and updating
and doing the other stuff in the SDL
like basic security training I mean
people are often hiring in from industry
or or from colleges and none of them if
they've done maybe one course in cyber
security they don't even know the the
fundamentals of it uh and a big
differentiator for partners going
forward will be the fact that they've
got a good security profile uh you know
and that they can actually attest to the
fact that we've had no incidents
>> uh and that they've done well
>> by the way I I want to use the
opportunity to say if you get a call
from somebody saying they're from
Microsoft and there's some security
issue on your computer this is not us
>> this is definitely not us I mean you can
confirm Well, we we don't call people
>> never
>> uh we don't we don't actively call
people and telling them there is a virus
on the computer. So the these are people
trying actually to get you to install
some
>> some malware of some kind somewhere on
your computer. Yeah, these are sports.
>> They usually what they do is that they
they kind of, you know, pretend
try to make you believe there's
something on your computer and uh and
then, you know, try to guide you to some
link and get you to install something on
your computer so they can ask
a sort of a screen sharing software like
anyes or or team viewer and then they
they they they scam people, old people.
they're they're den thieves and you know
and it's funny because you you reminded
me that a lot of those people are
getting taken down now not by
necessarily technical means but by you
know uh a whole series of cyber security
heroes and heroins that are often
underserved. So we've often focused on
the technical people, the knock
analysts, the the deep packet
inspection, the AI engineers and prompt
engineers, the you know the network
engineers, but some of the most
effective cyber security stuff is in
fact uh legal and marketing.
>> Mhm.
>> It's awareness raising. It's I mean we
when we take down the infrastructure for
these ransomware gangs, this is lawyers
that are doing this. This is the digital
crimes unit at Microsoft. Mostly women,
mostly lawyers. And they have they have
probably a 10 times more effect than
some of the than than many of the
security teams do
>> because they are really disrupting the
sort of the bad busy.
>> Yeah. And that's that's another thing
which I think people don't realize is
that cyber security as a discipline is
extremely broad.
>> It's not just a narrow technical thing.
A lot of it's psychology. A lot of it's
convincing business people to take
something seriously or painting a story
of what would happen if a system were
compromised. M uh so I do think that the
it's evolving and I mean right now we're
in the in the AI age we are in a in a
good place because at this exact moment
in the arms race the defenders are are
are are helped by AI
>> you know AI is great at at information
compression. So for us now being able to
analyze logs at enormous speed and then
kept you know get it down.
>> Yeah. A lot of Yeah. A lot of work.
>> A lot of work is just like
>> analyzing tons of logs you know going
through some some really tedious work
for for a human being that can be done
exactly easily with AI these days
>> you know even things like threat
traditionally threat modeling. So you
know my day job is to often sit down for
multiple meetings and look at a system
try and understand it and work the team
through that process. But I've now got a
a co-pilot threat modeler with me
>> that's watching the transcript. I can
speak to it on the side and ask it
questions. Hey, is this uh is you know
is this a security antiattern? Yes, it
is. They shouldn't do that. Now, the the
genius for this thing is that as a human
being, it's hard for me to remember the
300 or so controls
>> that are that are that SDL controls that
apply to different systems. You know,
oh, if it's a Cosmos database, then
>> but that's trivally easy. So we if
people put the threat model through the
threat modeling co-pilot, it can then
assess it.
>> It can see all of the applicable
policies and compliance rules and
weaknesses
>> and this is a massively boosted uh my
team and I's ability to spot
>> risks and and problems. So this is a
case where
>> AI is transformational. Now another
thing I've heard actually
is really good at and being used
extensively for for detecting attacks
that usually when you you have you know
there's a lot of logging going on you
know in your network or something and
and usually when you have some attempts
there is there's some it's about finding
the outliers finding something that is
you know not not fitting the patterns
and it can be really really difficult
for a human because it's large amount of
data and AI extremely good at that kind
of thing. picking out, you know,
something that is not, you know,
tons of logs or large amount of data
which, you know, it would take, you
know, ages for for for for humans to go
through. AI can can pick that up and and
and sometimes it's nothing but sometimes
like, hey, you know, at least you can,
you know, you can get your attention on
some of these things before it happens.
>> Completely right. I think that the
there's two problems. One of the big
problems in in in in cyber security
especially for network operations
security operations centers is alert
fatigue. The other one is, you know,
drowning in a sea of signal and that's
the signal boosting that I turned
referred to earlier.
>> That information compression and the
forget about all that stuff. Look at
this. And also being able to make these
associations between dis desperate
things, impossible travel, plus that
person has had multiple resets plus
they've their phone number or you know
called and you know the AIs can put this
together and say ah this is a risk
profile. you know, it also helps us, you
know, because one of the things that we
know at the beginning of this, I
probably just sort of described myself
as a as a risk manager because
ultimately that's what we do. We're
always trying to manage manage risk and
and reduce it. And I think one of the
things which we are now able to do is we
can look at the entire estate across uh
Dynamics 365 and Power Platform and we
can say okay this is made up of hundreds
of services right that are assembled
together into products. So what the
customer sees is actually made up of
little disparate parts. Those are you
know there are there are variations
between the security maturity of those
different teams and services and their
capabilities and the complexities that
they have. Some have got inherent risk.
They've got a lot of uh attack surface
like things that can go wrong. Lots of
infrastructure. Sometimes they they've
got an inexperienced security manager
that maybe needs a bit of help. Now we
can assess all of those with the help of
the AIS and we can have this heat map so
that my team and I can focus on the the
services that need more support and more
help. Maybe they're doing a high-risisk
thing. Maybe they're focusing on now,
you know, MCP servers are all the rage
and you know this is a new thing and
everyone's rushing into to an area to
say yeah I'm going to ship it and we can
then say let's calm down let's give you
some centralized guidance let's like
focus on what's important so I mean
today uh you know because it's always an
arms race today it's benefiting the
defenders AI is transformational in
cyber security the defender for X series
of Microsoft products are all really
doing phenomenal work out there uh in
terms of helping customers sort through
the the chaff and being able to focus in
on what's important. We see huge wins in
terms of the the prevent the the
security assurance and preventative side
of things. Uh we also use it extensively
in incident response. When we had the
midnight visitor incident which was is
publicly recognized uh Microsoft's own
mail systems were compromised by a state
level actor.
>> Mhm. So what was that? That was um
>> you know yeah I mean without going into
details a state level actor was decided
to to sort of uh they used a technique
and they managed to access certain
mailboxes.
>> Ah yeah in there it was that was in the
news. So
>> it was in the news. There's nothing
nothing secret about it. But for us to
figure out all of the potentially
compromised identities and systems was
such a herculan task
>> that a normal cleanup operation for an
event of that scale could take years.
But because we were able to use the AI
systems and tools to again compress and
and do the various cross references and
to get all of this gargantuan amounts of
telemetry and weed it out that took it
down from, you know, from months to
weeks
>> uh and which was which in cyber security
terms is is like flash fast. It's it's
speed of light, you know.
>> Um so it's also very useful for incident
response and often we're retooling
ourselves around seeing how how we can
do this. So you know in the threat
modeling meetings I I used to have to
take notes whilst trying to understand a
system and think about all the threats
and think about and making judgments
about these threats
>> you know yay or nay can you ship
>> that's a that's a lot of cognitive
burden it's like a fighter pilot having
to deal with like you know five planes
at once
>> now you know co-pilot takes the notes
>> I don't have to worry about that it's
got a perfect record of coming up with
the action items I just have to sit
there think and talk
>> and it takes care of all that stuff so I
think that what we do need to be careful
of because now AIs are finding bugs zero
days uh AIS are used to make the old
guidance that oh you can spot a fishing
mail because they'll have spelling
errors in the age of chatpt and copilot
and claude and and Gemini that's no
longer true
>> so attackers and we have uh you know and
both anthropic and uh open a have
shipped information about how attackers
have they're trying to figure out well
how can we use this stuff
>> you know how can we weaponize these
techniques against people like us, but
they haven't really found a good use for
it yet.
>> So, we'll see.
>> We'll see how it rolls.
>> All right, I think we I mean, we could
talk about this for hours. I mean, if
you want I mean, we can do a if you want
we could do another episode about it. We
could talk, you know, for so much.
Let us know in the comment if you want
to hear more about it. But, so last
words, you know, what last
recommendation for, uh, for partners and
and and and Business Central, uh, you
know, channel, what what should they do
to stay secure? or you mentioned, you
know, you mentioned some things. You
know,
>> I I think that I'd really like to just
give them a message of of of hope.
>> It's not as bad as it looks. It's fine.
>> Okay,
>> we've got your back.
>> Uh, you know, do doing a a relatively
small amount of things like multiffactor
authentication, security development
life cycle,
>> even giving some thought, threat
modeling, giving some thought to if you
look at the deck, which we will share on
SMB security, keeping an inventory of
your things, making sure that it's
patched and up to date, doing basic
vetting of your stuff and so on. like a
few small things. You can go from the
bottom 5% to the top 5%. You can make
yourself a very hard target very easily.
And this is the tragedy of cyber
security.
>> The basics are the basics and the basics
are basic
>> get you an awful long way. And the hard
stuff you can leave it to us. That's why
you pay us.
>> You know, the the very hard stuff, the
the super advanced stuff and the
vigilance and the watching, the alerting
and the response. You can leave that to
people that do this every day and are
gifted at it.
>> So, you do your bit basics and we do
ours and we're going to be fine.
>> All right. All right. All right. Well,
thank you very much. Thanks, Jonathan.
Thank you for watching.